Wang Xiaotao

<Senior Front-End Engineer>

Information

Email: wxt2005@gmail.com

GitHub: https://github.com/wxt2005

Location: Hangzhou, Zhejiang, China mainland

Profile

I'm a self-learned front-end engineer. I'm interested in web development, especially in User Experience area. I love building customer-facing products, and target motivating.

I have 5 years of experience as a front-end engineer, and familiar with constructing and maintaining high-quality Single Page Applications.

Work Experience

Cainiao Network (Alibaba Group) (2017.08 - present)

Worked as major front-end engineer of Cainiao post station business project, designed and developed all front-end application it contains.

- Divided the main application into three micro parts: shopping, payment and order center. So that we could easily add new kinds of shopping pages anytime without touching our major trading codebase.
- Used React and Redux as the main framework, and as to asynchronous actions management, I integrated Reduxobservable into it.
- Used modular CSS to prevent class name conflict and makes CSS easy to maintain.
- Optimized cache policy and used split-chunk of webpack to decrease loading time significantly.

Maintaining the company's front-end infrastructure. We are using OSS to store our static assets and using CDN to accelerate it, and using Node.js server to render SAP entry HTML files just so we could rollback and grey publish them as needed.

Developed an Android native application called Cainiao Box.

DXY (2014.10 - 2017.08)

Worked as major front-end engineer of Insight (a medicine database web application).

- Used React and Redux to refactor all codebases. For preserving the ability for back-end to change the page layout as needed, we designed a kind of JSON Schema for React to render it dynamically.
- In this project, we introduced webpack to our front-end team for the first time.

Developed all pages in DXY mobile app's webview, and designed JS bridge for web page and native app to communicate with each other.

Refactored DXY BBS and DXY HR's pages, separated business logics from PHP and JSP, and put them into JavaScript modules, then we used require.js to load these modules. In thoses projects, we used Grunt or Grulp as build tools.

Developed a utility package for opening native Apps from webpages. We use Custom Scheme in Android, and Universal Link in iOS.

Side Projects

Browser Opener

A Mac app to help you maintain your web browser habit.

As a front-end engineer, I am using Chrome as my dev tool on a daily basis, however, Safari is my favorite browser in MacOS. I'm tired of copying and pasting links from browser to browser while opening URL in IM messages or emails.

To solve this problem, I developed Browser Opener, which can be used as a browser dispatcher to help you deciding which browser to open based on URL pattern.

This application is written in Swift, and it's currently on Mac App Store. The Product Hunt page of this project has achieved the 3rd position of that day.

Mac App Store Link: https://apps.apple.com/us/app/browseropener/id1387480496

Product Hunt Page: https://www.producthunt.com/posts/browseropener

Bangumi List

A website collecting all Japanese anime watch lists.

There has been a lot of Japanese anime come to Chinese video websites, like Bilibili, Youku or iQiyi, since 2013. But due to fragmentation of copyrights, it was hard to find them on one single website. That's why I started this project.

This project is also my playground for chasing cutting edge of front-end technologies. It was first written in plain HTML tables, and then be refactored to Angular, then jQuery, and finally React. I'm considering making it to a Progress Web Application recently.

Site Link: https://bgmlist.com

Skill

- HTML
- JavaScript
- jQuery

- CSS
- React
- Node.js

Education

Zhejiang Shuren University — Bachelor of Civil Engineering 2009-2013